JOSEPH E. PERSICO PAPERS (APAP030) 1910-2003
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
- Speeches and Writings, 1958-2003; 3; 1.17
  - Sub-series 2: Writings, 1958-2003; 3.2; 1 cubic foot
    - Opinion Piece New York Times, "When Quotes Can't Be Trusted", 1997 (Box 45, Folder 27)
    - Opinion Piece The Wall Street Journal, "Deception is Part of the Art of War, But Shhhhh!", 2002 (Box 45, Folder 28)
    - Opinion Piece New York Times, "Can Words Change Meaning?", Undated (Box 45, Folder 29)
    - Research Material, 1959; 1976 (Box 45, Folder 30)
    - Rockefeller Foundation Bellagio Study and Conference Center Residency, 1996-2002 (Box 45, Folder 31)
    - "Rockefeller in Retrospect"New York Archives, 2001 (Box 45, Folder 32)
    - "Too Much Crime...Too Little Justice", Report of the President's Advisory Board, National Institute of Justice, ca. 1980s (Box 45, Folder 33)
    - Upset, Proposed Book about 1948 Truman-Dewey Presidential Election, Correspondence and Proposal, 1996-1997 (Box 45, Folder 34)
    - Upset, Proposed Book about 1948 Truman-Dewey Presidential Election, Research Material, ca. 1968-1999 (Box 45, Folder 35)
    - Upset, Proposed Book about 1948 Truman-Dewey Presidential Election, Research Material, ca. 1968-1999 (Box 45, Folder 36)
    - "War Crimes Trials", for The Reader's Companion to Military History, 1994-1996 (Box 45, Folder 37)
    - "We May Never Mate Again"Times Union, 1999 (Box 45, Folder 38)
    - "Who knows? Who cares? Forgotten Children in Foster Care", Report of the National Commission on Children in Need of Parents, 1979 (Box 45, Folder 39)
- Correspondence, 1960-2002; 4; 1 cubic foot
  Correspondence to and from Persico can be found throughout the collection. For example, references to Persico's publications will be found in both the general correspondence files and the subseries of specific publications. While some correspondence is clearly personal or professional, there is not always a clear separation between the author's personal and professional correspondents. Persico appears to have retained copies of much of his outgoing correspondence in the form of typed and handwritten letters and email messages. The author's notable correspondents include: director John Huston who Persico interviewed for an article in American Heritage; Pulitzer Prize-winning authors Michael Shaara (1983) and William Kennedy (1983); journalist Jim Lehrer (1986); Broadway and television director Edwin Sherin (1985); author Thomas Powers (1993); and Casey Murrow (1995, 1998) among others.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Correspondence, 1960; 1983-1994 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Janklow, Mort, Correspondence, 1978-1985 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Huston, John, Correspondence, 1982 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Bernard Geis Associates, Correspondence, 1982-1984 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Publications, Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1995 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1997 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1998 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1998 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1999 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 2001 (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 2001 (Box 46, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 2001 (Box 46, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 2002 (Box 46, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 2002 (Box 46, Folder 19)
- Biographical, 1958-2001; 5; 0.17 2 films
  The Biographical series is predominantly material from early in Persico's career. Included are folders related to his election as the Executive Secretary of the New York State Young Democrats in 1958 and his time as a Foreign Service Officer in Latin America. Of particular biographical note are the scrapbook and news clippings folders which include selected highlights from throughout Persico's career in government service and as an author.
  - Latin America, ca. 1959-1962 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Letter to the Editor, Anonymous, 1963 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Persico, News Clippings, 1975-2001 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Resume, 1966 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Saint Rose Cup Polo Match, Scholarship, 1997 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook, ca. 1959-1990 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Young Democrats, 1958 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - "The Naked Writer" Lecture for the New York State Writers Institute, University at Albany, Page Hall, Master and Use Copies, VHS, 2001 March 14 (Box 47)